

[Bukhari Kusuma Alam]

South Jakarta, DKI Jakarta, 12320 | +62 877 3917 7831 | <u>kusumaalam@gmail.com</u> Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/bukhari-kusuma-alam-4ba95857

ABOUT ME

My name Bukhari Kusuma Alam, Under graduate from Diponegoro University majoring in Naval Architecture, graduated at September 2019. Have working experience as Project Manager at for NIKE footwear development at PT. Pratama Abadi Industri since November 2020 until now. Also have experience working as business development for BTA Almamater from July 2020 until September 2020, Quality Control internship at IPC Marine on 2018, and Internship at Production Divison PT. Dok & Perkapalan Kodja Bahari on 2017. Have organization Experince as Division Leader and staff. Can operate working software such as MS. Office and 2D&3D software such as Auto CAD and Rhinoceros. Fluently communicate in English verbally and written.

SKILL & COMPETANCY

- Microsoft Office
- AutoCAD
- Rhinoceros 3D Modeling
- Solidwork

- Tydn CFD analysis
- Poster Design
- Content Writing
- English

WORK EXPERIENCE

PT. Pratama Abadi Industri (South Tangerang, Indonesia)

Project Manager for NIKE footwear development (November 2020 - Now)

- Responsible for over 50 Project development of 3 NIKE's footwear model in a year.
- Shipped project successfully with best quality and with delivery on time rate at 95%
- Connect with client / buyer (NIKE) related to, understanding the requirement, tracking project status, resolve discrepancies, and evaluate solution.
- Responsible for the implementation of various improvement needed to support the client / buyer need.
- Connect with cross function department to identify any potential issues and provide solution to client / buyer.
- Managed and supervising prototyping samples and follow through commercialization to initial mass production.
- Developed and specified material, component construction, and any other project specification to meet pricing target, and product functional goals.
- Conduct project inquisition meeting to identify key points of the project.

Bimbingan Belajar BTA Almamater (Cibubur, Indonesia)

Business Development & Marketing (July 2020 – September 2020)

- Get 5 new member of student's and re-attract 15 old student's in the first month, improving average likes to 300% on social media, and reaching out 200% more people in social media.
- Responsible on the content of company social media, promoting and developing company existence, evaluate the overall performance and helping communicate with student guardian.

PT. IPC Marine (Jakarta, Indonesia)

Quality Control Internship (August 2018 - September 2018)

 Supervise the quality and accuracy of the vessel reparation, while learning project scheduling of ship reparation.

PT. Dok & Perkapalan Kodja Bahari (Jakarta, Indonesia)

Production Internship (Agustus 2018 - September 2018)

 Supervise the workflow of New Ship Building project and ship reparation, and learning ship docking process.

EDUCATION

Diponegoro University (2015-2019)

Undergraduate of Naval Architecture - GPA 3.35

- Published a journal on International Review of Mechanical Engineering (IREME) with title: Numerical Investigation of Hydrodynamic Behavior of Foil Shaped Zinc Anode for Reducing the Hull Appendages Effect
- Active on organization in the Naval Architecture Student Association of Diponegoro University since 2016 to 2018 as the Head of Student Resource Development Division.

90 Public Senior Highschool Jakarta (2012-2015)

Science Major.

ORGANIZATION

Naval Architecture Student Association of Diponegoro University (July 2016 - March 2018)

Head of Student Resource Development Division (April 2017 – March 2018)

 Responsible for division member skill development and in charge on skill and character development for candidate of new student member at Naval Architecture of Diponegoro University.

Staff of Student Resource Development Division (April 2016 – March 2017)

 Working in the team to develop the skill and character for candidate of new student member at Naval Architecture of Diponegoro University.

Courses, Workshop and Certification

- Google UX Design Coursera (Currently)
- Learning Graphic Design Skill Academy (2020)
- Agile and Scrum Application for Program Development Skill Academy (2020)

Projects

NIKE Footwear Development

- In charge on over 50 Project Development of NIKE Footwear Product.
- Handling 3 different model of NIKE Footwear Product: NIKE Air Max Plus, NIKE Air Zoom 2K, NIKE Waffle Trainer 2.

Community Service Program at Warung Asem Village, Batang (2019)

- Educate local student about the urgency of advanced education.
- Helping on designing a tourism facility to help on improving villager economy and income.
- Share the information to villager about the importance on recycling for better environment.

Badong Village Volunteer, Demak (2016-2018)

- Routine fun class for kids to improve their knowledge and insight.
- Mangrove cultivation to preventing the village abrasion.